YING WANG

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

303.847.2762

yingw.pro@gmail.com

https://github.com/yingwerica

Broomfield, CO

PROFILE

A full stack software developer with **MERN** stack skills with Per Scholas certification. An aspirant **team player** and a certified **Scrum Master** with over six years experience of customer-oriented product/project management in IT and global business industries. A **never-stop learner** who is an **energetic problem solver** and ready to make positive impacts.

EXPERIENCE

Product Manager | 5173.COM | Shanghai, China | 2008-2012

- Innovated a new online marketplace trading process "from buyer to seller" and officially launched online in 2009.
- Established an account security and user blacklist system with the customer service department.
- Facilitated User module architecture design of the entire website.

Project Management Engineer | Advantech Co., Ltd | China | 2006-2008

- Established a new sourcing process with vendors on consignment parts. Increased 1500 customer orders with gross of \$170, 000 annually.
- Carried out schemes of a rework plan to solve the power failure issue after production on ESM-2640 module.
- Led the special processing to deliver 12pcs samples within 20 days fulfilling an urgent order from a valuable customer.

Sales | Coach | Thornton, Colorado | 2017-2018

- Ranked #1 in salesmanship in 2018 of the entire store.
- Maintained the top rank of the sales performance and productivity level (16.7 VS. goal 9.6).
- Conducted practical and creative sales model on Black Friday sale event to improve sales performance by 13%.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Certificate | Software Engineering | Per Scholas & ActivateWork | 2022-2023 Certificate | ScrumMaster | Scrum Alliance | 2020- Now Bachelor of Engineering | Xidian University | 2002-2006

VOLUNTEERING

- Recreation activities such as Mud Hen 5K | City of Longmont | 2017-2018
- Chinese New Year Celebration | Asian-Pacific Association of Longmont |
 2017-2019
- Chinese women career development | Denver Professional Chinese Women Association | 2020-Now
- Board member | Xidian University Alumni Association of America | 2020-Now
- Monthly appreciation arrangement to the teachers/staff | Sunshine Committee in Prospect Ridge Academy | 2022-Now

CORE COMPETENCIES

MERN Stack:

- MongoDB
- Express.js
- React.js
- Node.js

Languages:

- JavaScript
- Java
- Python
- MySQL

Environments:

- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- ES6
- Mongoose
- NPM
- JSON
- REST API
- MVC
- CRUD
- Redux
- Visual Studio Code
- Git, GitHub
- Chrome/React Dev Tools
- Postman

Soft Skills:

- Teamwork
- Critical Thinking
- Problem Solving
- Adaptability
- Agile Project
 Management
- Bilingual
 Communication in
 English and Chinese